Country. PIN - 500032

RAMESHA GOLA

rameshqola9@qmail.com

SUMMARY

Data scientist and Data Analyst with More than Two years of tech industry experience in a wide range of functions including predictive modeling, statistical analysis, Data visualization, Machine learning algorithms, Model development and product analytics.

SKILLS

Data analysis, Machine Learning algorithms, Data Visualization, Hadoop, Python, Anaconda, MySQL, Mathematics, Data Mining, Statistical analysis, Predictive modeling, Model Development.

WORK EXPERIENCE

DATA SCIENTIST.

PHATAKE GLOBAL SERVICES.

JUNE 2020 — MAY 2021

• **Linear regression (project)**— In this section, we have built a Linear Regression model to predict Sales using an appropriate predictor variable.

RESPONSIBILITIES -

- **DATA UNDERSTANDING**: In this process need to load the Data and understand the attributes meaning, shape of Dataset etc.
- **Data Analysis**: Data analysis involves manipulating, transforming and visualizing data in order to infer meaningful insights from the results.
- **Data Visualization**: methods used to summarize the distribution and relationships between variables using visualization such as charts, graphs and plots.
- Statistical analysis: the statistical methods used to clean and prepare data ready for modelling.
- Data preprocessing: Rescaling the variables, splitting into train and test Data sets etc.
- **MODEL Development:** Building the linear model
- HYPER PARAMETER TUNING: K-Fold Cross Validation, Grid Search to find optimal Hyper parameter C
- **OPTIMIZING FOR OTHER EVALUATION METRICS:** in this case, we had optimized the model based on the accuracy though that may not always be the best metrics to optimize.

DATA SCIENTIST. JUNE 2019 - DEC 2019

PEOPLE CLICK TECHNO SOLUTIONS.

• CREDIT CARD DEFAULT PREDICTION (project):- in this lab, we will build a random Forest model to predict the whether a given customer defaults or not. Credit default is one of the most import problem in the banking and risk analytics. There are various attributes which can be used to predict default, such as demographical Data behavioral Data etc.

TECHNOLOGIES USED-PYTHON, EXCEL, AND SQL.

RESPONSIBILITIES –

- **DATA UNDERSTANDING:** In this process need to load the Data and understand the attributes meaning, shape of Dataset etc.
- **Data Analysis**: Data analysis involves manipulating, transforming and visualizing data in order to infer meaningful insights from the results.
- **Data Visualization**: methods used to summarize the distribution and relationships between variables using visualization such as charts, graphs and plots.
- · Statistical analysis: the statistical methods used to clean and prepare data ready for modelling.
- Data preprocessing: Rescaling the variables, splitting into train and test Data sets etc.
- · MODEL Development: Building Random forest model
- HYPER PARAMETER TUNING: K-Fold Cross Validation, Grid Search to find optimal Hyper parameter C
- **OPTIMIZING FOR OTHER EVALUATION METRICS:** in this case, we had optimized the model based on the accuracy though that may not always be the best metrics to optimize

DATA ANALYST.

PRAGATHI AUTOMATION AND SERVICES.

JAN 2018 - MAY 2018

· Pragathi automation and services is service based company which services to company like RICOH.

TECHNOLOGIES USED – EXCEL, POWER POINT.

RESPONSIBILITIES -

- As a Data analyst I have been worked with the sales and services team.
- Developed and Implemented new marketing and sales plans and defined the strategy for the next Few years
- Reviewed constantly the customer feedback and then suggested ways to improve the process and customer service levels which increased the customer satisfaction.
- Ensured that new clients will grow into loyal customer base in a specialist niche market by implementing a new loyalty program

TECHNOLOGIES AND LANGUAGES

- · HANDS ON PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES PYTHON (VISUALIZATION, MODEL BUILDING, ETC.)
- **ANALYTICAL TOOLS** Python, Excel, mysql.
- MACHINE LEARNING Linear regression, Logistic regression, Time Series, Decision Tree, Random Forest, K-Means, SVM, Hierarchical clustering, PCA, Advance Regression etc.
- · DATABASE MYSQL.
- · PLATFORMS AND MISC. ANACONDA, JUPYTER NOTEBOOK

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Mechanical Engineering with aggregate of 65% (2017)2014-2017Visvesvaraya Technological University, Belgaum